Joe Zhang

Student

Address 54 Westgate Rd #3, Plainfield, NH, 03781

Phone (603) 277-0966

E-mail zhangjoe99@gmail.com

LinkedIn https://www.linkedin.com/in/joe-zhang-7a6b441a3/

Year of 2021 at Dartmouth College majoring in Computer Science with a passion for coding and mathematics. Strong math, logic and organizational skills and focused attention to detail. Familiar with programming languages: Python, C, R, Java. Experienced in research in a computer lab and an immunology lab; skills include teamwork in software development, creating and keeping deadlines, problem solving, and more.



Work Experience/Relevant Experience

Jun 2017 -Jun 2019

Research Assistant in Immunology Laboratory

(PI) Mary Jo Turk, Dartmouth College, Hanover, NH

- Researched Memory T cells in mice and its effects on melanoma growth to better understand autoimmune diseases.
- Performed PCR, mouse surgery/takedowns, Western blots, managing cell cultures, data analysis
- Worked with Flow Jo, R (programming language), Seurat (Satija Lab), and Dartmouth super computer "Discovery"
- Analyzed flow cytometry data, binding strength of epitopes to MHC, single-cell RNA-seq data, variant calling analysis

Mar 2019 -Jun 2019

Awarded Sophomore Research Scholar (Dartmouth)

Laboratory Of Bo Zhu, Hanover, NH

- Research different types of fluids and their properties to model them in computer simulations
- Using Pybind to make existing C++ code compatible with Python

Mar 2020 -Mar 2020

Smartphone Programming

Eye Spy, Android App (Group Of 4)

- Designed, implemented, tested, and debugged a smartphone applications for assisting the visually impaired
- Worked with java, phone sensors, threads, background services, and cloud programming using Firebase
- Project website: https://eyespyapp910147145.wordpress.com/



Education

Sep 2017 -Current

Bachelor of Arts: Computer Science

Dartmouth College - Hanover, NH

- GPA: 3.2/4.0
- Relevant Coursework: Object Oriented Programming, Algorithms, Software Design and Implementation, Smartphone Programming, Full-Stack Web Development, Machine Learning and Statistical Data Analysis, Artificial Intelligence, Principles of Robot Design and Programming
- Activities: Member of Zeta Psi Fraternity, Member of Agape Christian Fellowship, Computer Science Tutor



Skills



Computer Skills: Java, Python, C, R, HTML, JavaScript, Microsoft Office, Unity, Gamemaker

Interpersonal Skills: Problem Solving, Data Analysis, Teamwork, Communication